&gt;&gt; Hello, good afternoon and
&gt;&gt; 大家好下午好
welcome to session 509,
欢迎来到 509 分会场
Introducing AirPlay 2 Unlocking
我将为大家介绍 AirPlay 2
Multi-Room Audio.
的多房间音频控制功能
My name is David Saracino, I'm a
我叫 David Saracino
member of the AirPlay
是 AirPlay 工程团队的
engineering team, and I'm very
一名成员
excited to be here this
今天非常高兴能来到这里
afternoon to talk to you about
和大家讨论
the many new features we've
我们在过去一年来
added to audio to AirPlay over
为 AirPlay 音频新添的众多功能
the last year, and how you can
以及如何怎样才能
adopt them in your app.
将这些功能嵌入你们的 App 里
But before we get into that
在我们开始
adoption and how you can build
介绍之前
this into your app, let's first
让我们先来
take a quick survey of AirPlay
快速回顾一下当前的 AirPlay
today, and where we're taking it
并就我们想把 AirPlay 2 带向何方
with AirPlay 2.
做一个说明
So, with AirPlay today, you can
应用现在的 AirPlay 你能够
wirelessly send your myriad
将海量的屏幕画面
screen, audio, or video content
音频或视频内容以无线的方式
from just about any Apple device
从任何一部苹果设备
to an Apple TV or AirPlay
投射到苹果电视或
speaker.
支持 AirPlay 的音箱中
Over the past year, we've added
过去一年来我们着重
so many features to the audio
在音频版块
domain that that's where we're
新增了许多功能
going to spend the majority of
这也将是我今天演讲的
our talk.
主要内容
And because we've added so many
正因为我们在音频版块
features to the audio domain
新增了这么多功能
we're introducing this as a new
我们将它们集合为一个新的整体
feature called AirPlay 2.
叫做 AirPlay 2
So, what is AirPlay 2?
所以什么是 AirPlay 2
Well with AirPlay 2, you can
用 AirPlay 2 你仍然可以
still wirelessly send the audio
以无线方式将音频内容
content from your app to an
从你的 App 发送到
AirPlay speaker.
支持 AirPlay 的音箱
But additionally, with AirPlay
但是同时有 AirPlay 2 以后
2, you can send that content to
你可以把那段音频
multiple AirPlay 2 speakers with
几乎同步地发送到多个
very tight sync.
多个支持 AirPlay 2 的音箱
Additionally, in AirPlay 2,
此外我们还
we've enhanced the audio
改进了支持 AirPlay 2 的音箱
buffering on the AirPlay 2
存在的音频缓冲问题
speakers so that your content
以便让音频内容的
can play with the high degree of
播放环境更稳定
robustness, reliability, and
更可靠
responsiveness.
反应更加灵敏
And lastly, we're introducing
最后我们还将
multi-device control.
介绍多设备控制功能
And this will allow multiple
这一功能将允许
Apple devices in your home to
你家中的
interact with the audio that's
多个苹果设备
being streamed throughout your
与房间中的音频流
house.
进行互动
So, where is AirPlay 2
那么都有哪些地方
supported?
支持 AirPlay 2 呢？
Well I'm happy to say if you
我非常高兴地告诉你
have iOS, tvOS, or macOS app,
如果你有 iOS Apple tvOS 或 macOS 应用
you can take the steps that I'm
你就可以按照我一会儿将
about to outline today and build
介绍的大致步骤
them into your app to take
将 AirPlay 2 功能
advantage of AirPlay 2.
运用到你的 App 中
And when you do, your app will
当你这样做之后
be able to play on a very wide
你的 App 将能够在一个广阔的
ecosystem of AirPlay 2 speakers,
AirPlay  2 播放器生态系统里运行
including the HomePod, latest
其中包括 HomePod
generation Apple TV, and
最新一代苹果电视
third-party AirPlay 2 speakers
以及即将投放市场的
that will soon be coming to
支持 AirPlay 2 的
market.
第三方音箱
So, that's the high-level
以上就是对于
overview of AirPlay and AirPlay
AirPlay 以及 AirPlay 2
2.
高度概括的介绍
Let's look at our agenda for the
让我们看看本场介绍会
rest of the talk.
接下来的内容
First, we're going to talk about
首先我们将谈一谈
basic AirPlay 2 adoption.
AirPlay 2 的基本嵌入步骤
The steps that you need to do
也就是为了将
take in order to get AirPlay 2
AirPlay 2 引入你的 App
inside your app.
需要采取的步骤
Next, we're going to focus on
之后我们将重点讨论
some advanced playback scenarios
一些更加高级的播放场景
that you may encounter as you
在你嵌入 AirPlay 2 时
adopt AirPlay 2.
可能会遇到这些问题
And lastly, we're going to talk
最后我们将谈到
about the availability of
AirPlay 2 的
AirPlay 2.
可用性
So, let's begin our talk about
那么我们先来谈谈
AirPlay 2 adoption.
AirPlay 2 的嵌入
So, in order to adopt AirPlay 2
为了在 App 中
in your app, there are basically
嵌入 AirPlay 2
four steps you need to take.
基本上要采取 4 个步骤
First, you should identify your
第一步必须声明你的 App
app as presenting long-form
提供的是
audio.
长音频
I'll explain what long-form
我一会儿再解释
audio is in a minute.
什么是长音频
Next, you should add an AirPlay
第二步要在 App 中添加一个
picker inside your app.
AirPlay 选择器
And third, you should integrate
第三步要将
with certain parts of the
MediaPlayer 框架的
MediaPlayer framework.
某些部分整合进去
And lastly, you should adopt one
最后一步 要引入
of the playback APIs that are
一个带有播放选项的 API
specifically designed to take
以便充分利用
advantage of the enhanced
经过改进的
buffering in AirPlay 2.
AirPlay 2 缓冲系统
So, let's walk through each of
接下来让我们
these individually.
逐一讲解这些步骤
First, identifying yourself as
首先要声明你自己
presenting long-form audio
提供的是
content.
长音频内容
So, what is long-form audio
所以到底什么是
Well long-form audio is anything
长音频内容就是比如
like, is content like music,
像是音乐
podcasts, or audiobooks, as
播客或是有声书
distinct from things like system
这种音频与苹果电脑短促的
sounds on a Mac.
系统声音完全不同
Now, identifying yourself as
声明你自己是
presenting long-form audio
长音频内容的提供者
content is very easy.
非常容易
You simply set your
你只要把  App  中
application's AVAudioSession's
AVAudioSession  的
route sharing policy to be
路由共享策略
long-form.
设置为长形的
Now here's a code snippet of how
这里是如何在 iOS 上操作的
you do that on iOS.
代码片段
This is something that many of
许多 iOS 开发人员
you iOS developers are likely
可能对于设置
familiar with setting your
分类和模式
category and mode, and there's
比较熟悉
just a new parameter here which
刚才提到的只是一个新的参数
is routeSharingPolicy:
路由共享策略:.长形
.longform.
(RouteSharingPolicy:.longform.)
As I said, this has been around
这个参数在
on iOS for a little while.
iOS 上已经
This class is actually,
存在了一段时间了
AVAudioSession is new altogether
AVAudioSession 在苹果电脑操作系统中
on macOS, and I'm not going to
是新出现的
show a code snippet, but it's
我不会在此展示代码片段
even simpler than what you have
不过代码比你在 iOS 上写的
to do on iOS.
还要简单
You simply set the route sharing
你只要把路由共享策略
policy to long-form.
设置为长形
And for more information on this
有关这个路由共享策略的
new route sharing policy and
更多介绍
what it can do for your app in
以及它还能为你的 App
regards to the rest of the
做些什么
system, for example allow the
例如允许用户在
user to take a phone call while
使用 App 进行 AirPlay 投射时
you're app is AirPlay, using
接电话
AirPlay 2 to stream to speakers,
使用 AirPlay 2 将音频发送到音箱上
I encourage you to take a look
我希望你们能
at this session from earlier in
观看本周早些时候举行的另一个介绍会
the week called What's New in
它的题目是 What's New in
Audio.
Audio
All right, so that's the first
好的 以上就是使用 AirPlay 2
step you need to do to take
需要做的
advantage of AirPlay 2.
第一步
The second is to add an AirPlay
第二步是在 App 中添加
picker inside your app.
AirPlay 选择器
This will allow users to route
它将使用户能够
their content to AirPlay
在 App 的使用范围内
speakers without leaving the
把他们的内容传输到
confines of your app.
AirPlay 音箱
And doing this is very easy.
做法很简单
You simply adopt a new API
你只要嵌入
called AVKit's
一个新的 API
AVRoutePickerView.
叫做 AVKit'sAVRoutePickerView
You simply add this view to your
把这个界面
view hierarchy.
加到你的界面层级中
And you may want to control when
你可能想要控制
this is shown, for example only
这个界面什么时候出现
show it if there actually is an
例如当发现支持 AirPlay 或
AirPlay 2 speaker or an AirPlay
AirPlay 2 的音箱时
speaker available to be routed
才让它
to.
出现
And you can do that by adopting
你可以嵌入
AVFoundation's AVRouteDetector
AVFoundation'sAVRouteDetector
which will tell you if there are
它将在发现音箱
speakers, if there are routes
有传输路径时
available.
会通知你
These API, they're new in the
这些 API
latest OS releases and they're
在最新的操作系统中都有
available on macOS, iOS, and
包括 macOS iOS
tvOS.
和 Apple tvOS
And a note to all of you iOS
提醒一下正在使用
developers who are currently
MPVolumeView 的
using MPVolumeView, it will
iOS 开发工程师
still work, but we are
它将继续工作
encouraging people to move to
但我们鼓励大家
these API instead.
使用这些新的 API
So, that's the second thing you
以上是如何在 App 中
need to do to get your app up
充分利用 AirPlay 2
and running with AirPlay 2.
的第二个步骤
The third thing you should do is
你要做的第三件事是
to integrate your app with
将你的 App
certain parts of the MediaPlayer
与 MediaPlayer 框架下的部分内容进行
framework.
整合
Now this is rather large, so
这部分内容比较多
there's basically two things
所以我今天
that I'm specifically focusing
只重点讲
on today.
两件事
And these are things that will,
这些事情
these API will allow you to do
这些 API 将让你
things like display the
能够在锁屏上
currently playing album art on
或者是被 AirPlay 投射的苹果电视上
the lock screen or an Apple TV
显示正在播放的专辑图片
it's being AirPlayed to.
等信息
And additionally, they will
同时它们将
allow you to receive playback
让你能够接收
commands and pause commands from
来自网络中其他设备
other devices on the network or
或是耳机等配件的
from other accessories like
播放以及暂停
headphones.
命令
And the two pieces of API that
我们需要的两个 API
we need, we are asking you to
我们希望你能
adopt.
嵌入它们
The first is
第一个是
MPRemoteCommandCenter and this
MPRemoteCommandCenter
will allow you to receive those
它将允许你接收
remote commands, and the second
远程命令
is MPNowPlayingInfoCenter which
第二个是 MPNowPlayingInfoCenter
will allow you to inform the
它将允许你
system metadata about the
将正在播放的曲目
currently playing track.
通知给元数据系统
All right, so that's the third
好的 以上就是
thing you need to do to get your
你在 App 中使用 AirPlay 2
app up and running with AirPlay
需要做的
2.
第三件事
The fourth this is you should
第四件事是
adopt one of the playback APIs
你应该嵌入一个
that are specifically designed
控制播放的 API
to take advantage of enhanced
以充分利用
buffering in AirPlay 2.
AirPlay 2 的升级版缓冲系统
And to motivate this
为了让大家更好地理解
conversation, let's take a look
我们来深入了解一下
a little bit deeper at AirPlay
AirPlay 的音频和
audio and the buffer levels
缓冲级别
beginning with how AirPlay works
首先来了解一下
today.
现在的 AirPlay 是如何工作的
So, AirPlay today is effectively
当前的 AirPlay 实际上是
a real-time stream of audio to
一个实时的音频流
which the speakers adds just a
接收的音箱只需要
few seconds of buffering before
几秒钟的缓冲时间
playing out in real-time.
就可以流畅播放了
Now, this works very well to a
目前这个功能对于
single speaker, and it works
单个音箱来说表现很好
pretty well with lots of
在播放海量内容时
content.
也工作顺畅
But, if we are able to restrict
不过
ourselves on only focusing on
如果我们只重点针对长音频
long-form content, like music,
进一步开发例如音乐播客
podcasts or audiobooks, we can
或者是有声书
probably do better.
我们可能会取得更大进步
So, let's talk about the
让我们来谈谈
enhanced buffering in AirPlay 2.
AirPlay 2 中经过改进的缓冲系统
So, what am I talking about with
我所说的经过改进的
enhanced buffering in AirPlay 2?
AirPlay 2 缓冲系统是指什么呢？
Well, as the name implies, we've
正如名称所指的
added very large buffer capacity
我们使支持 AirPlay 2 的音箱
on the AirPlay 2 speakers.
增加了非常大的缓冲能力
Here I want you to think
现在我希望你能就此认真思考
minutes, not seconds.
几分钟 而不是几秒钟
Additionally, we're able to
此外我们能够
stream the audio content from
以比实时还要快的速度
your app to the speaker
将音频内容
faster-than-real-time.
从你的 App 传输到音箱上
And I think the benefits of this
这项改进的优势
should be clear.
显而易见
The large buffering on the
AirPlay 音箱的巨大缓冲能力
AirPlay speakers will add a
能够大幅增加
large degree of robustness to
AirPlay 的
the AirPlay session.
稳定性
You should be able to survive
同时能对抗
more typical network glitches,
更多的常见网络故障
like walking, taking the trash
例如你在走路外出倒垃圾
out, or walking to the dead spot
或走到屋内的死角
of the house, or even
甚至是
microwaving some popcorn.
在微波爆米花时
Additionally, this should
此外它还能
provide more responsive playback
提供更加富有回应性的
experience.
播放体验
The real-time nature of existing
目前的 AirPlay
AirPlay means that there's a
所拥有的实时属性
fixed output latency that is
意味着存在一个与 AirPlay 音箱
related to the buffer level on
缓冲级别有关的
the AirPlay speaker.
固定的输出延迟时间
So, when you hit play, with
所以当你按下播放键
AirPlay 2 it should play a lot
AirPlay 2 将更快
faster.
开始播放
When you hit skip, it should
当你按下一曲按键
skip a lot faster.
它也会更快地做出反应
This will add a great, this is a
这将带来
great user experience for your
更好的用户体验
users which is why we're really
这也是为什么我们
excited to talk about the
如此兴奋地向大家介绍
enhanced buffering.
新的缓冲系统
And so in order to take
为了充分利用
advantage of the advanced
经过改进的缓冲系统
buffering, you should adopt one
你应该嵌入
of a few API.
几组 API 中的一组
The first, is AVPlayer and
第一组是 AVPlayer
AVQueuePlayer.
以及 AVQueuePlayer
The AVPlayer's set of playback
AVPlayer 拥有一组
API.
播放 API
These have been around for quite
它们已经推出了一段时间
a while and they're your easiest
并且是通往 AirPlay 2
route to AirPlay 2 in the
新缓冲系统
enhanced buffering.
最便捷的路径
The second API, set of API are
第二组 API
new API that we're introducing
是我们今天要介绍的
today which are
新事物
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer and
叫做 AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer
AVSampleBufferRender
以及 AVSampleBufferRender
Synchronizer.
Synchronizer
These will prevent, present more
它们会让
flexibility to apps that need
App 的灵活性
it.
得到提升
So, let's talk about these
那么 让我们逐一来
individually by first surveying
谈谈这些 API
AVPlayer and AVQueuePlayer.
首先是 AVPlayer 和 AVQueuePlayer
So, as I've said these have been
正如我所说
around for quite a while, since
它们已经推出了一段时间
iOS 4 on the iOS platforms.
在 iOS  4 时就有了
And because of that there's a
正因如此
ton of documentation on the
在开发者网站上有大量的存档记录
developer website and a lot of
还有很多的
sample code there.
样本代码
So, if you want a lot of detail
所以如果你想要获得详细的信息
on these, I encourage you to
我鼓励你去
look to the developer website,
查看开发者的网站
because I'm just going to give a
在这里我只打算给出
very high-level overview of
关于这些 API 的高度概括的
these API today.
介绍
So, what I'm going to do, is I'm
我接下来要做的
going to walk through what it
是将粗略介绍一遍
takes to build an app with this
如何用这个 API
API.
建立 App
So, here you have your Client
这里是你的 ClientApp
App, and if you want to build an
如果你想用 AVPlayer
app with an AVPlayer or
或 AVQueuePlayer 来建立 App
AVQueuePlayer, the first thing
首先要做的就是
you're going to do is your going
将这些对象中的一个
instantiate one of the objects.
实例化
Here I'm using an AVQueuePlayer
我在这里使用的是 AVQueuePlayer
but the steps are exactly the
如果你用 AVPlayer 的话
same if you use AVPlayer.
步骤是一样的
Next, you're going to take a URL
接下来你要把
that points to the content that
指向你播放内容的 URL
you want to play, and that
当然这个内容可以是
content can be local or it can
存在本地的
be in the cloud, it can be
或是在云端的
remote.
它可以是在远端的
You're going to take that URL,
你把这个 URL
and you're going to wrap it in
放在 AVAsset 里
an AVAsset and you're going to
再把这个 AVAsset
wrap that AVAsset in an
放在
AVPlayerItem.
AVPlayerItem 里面
Next, you're going to give that
接下来你要把
AVPlayerItem to the
这个 AVPlayerItem
AVQueuePlayer.
放到 AVQueuePlayer
Now after you've handed it over,
在你把它移交过去之后
you're ready to initiate
你就准备好可以启动
playback.
播放了
And you do so but simply setting
你只需简单将
the rate of 1 on the
AVQueuePlayer 的 rate 设置为 1
AVQueuePlayer, which in response
它就会开始
will begin downloading the audio
下载音频数据
data from wherever it resides,
然后在
and then playing it out the
音箱中
speakers.
播放
So, this is the quick survey of
这就是对 AVPlayer 和 AVQueuePlayer 的
AVPlayer and AVQueuePlayer, I
简要介绍
should also note that this works
以上内容同样适用于
really well for video content.
视频文件
So, if you want to play some
如果你想播放
video content, you can do it
视频内容
pretty easily with AVPlayer and
用 AVPlayer 和 AVQueuePlayer
AVQueuePlayer.
也能轻松搞定
So, just to reiterate, your
再强调一遍
easiest way to AirPlay 2 is
AirPlay 2 最简单的使用方法
using these API.
就是通过这些 API
But we recognize that this won't
不过我们也明白
work for everybody.
可能不是人人都这么认为
There's a certain class of audio
可能有这样一类
playing apps that either
音频播放 App
require, that want to do their
它们想要有
own IO possibly.
自己的 IO
Possibly their own DRM or even
自己的 DRM
preprocessing on the media data
甚至在媒体数据被渲染之前
before it's rendered out.
对它进行预处理
They need more flexibility than
这些 App 需要更多的灵活性
the, than what these API
这是刚才那些 API
provide.
无法提供的
And for these developers we're
对于这些开发者
introducing these new classes,
我们想介绍以下这些新类别
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer and
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer 和
AVSampleBufferRender
AVSampleBufferRender
Synchronizer.
Synchronizer
Now with these APIs when you use
用这组新的 API
them to do playback, your app
来设置播放的话
has additional responsibilities.
你的 App 就要承担额外的责任
So, first of all your app is
首先你的 App
responsible for sourcing and
要负责找到播放内容的来源
parsing the content.
并对其解析
You need to go get it wherever
你需要到源头去获取内容
it is, download it, read it off
不管是下载还是从光盘上读取
disc, whatever.
都可以
And then your app has to parse
然后你的 App 必须去解析它
it and feed the raw audio data,
并得到原始音频数据
the raw audio buffers to the API
原始音频数据缓冲到 API
for rendering.
再进行渲染
This is kind of similar to
这有点类似于
AudioQueue but it works better
AudioQueue 但它在
with the deeper buffers that we
更强缓冲能力下 会表现得更好
need for buffered AirPlay, for
例如拥有更好缓冲系统的
enhanced AirPlay.
AirPlay
Because these are new, we're
正因为这些都是新的内容
going to spend the remainder of
我们这场介绍会余下的时间
this session talking about
都将用来
these.
介绍它们
All right, so let's walk through
好的 让我们来看一下
a simple block diagram of how
一个简单的框图
you might build an app using
介绍如何用这些 API
these API.
来建立 App
So, again use your Client App,
再一次使用你的 Client App
and the first thing you're going
建立 App 你首先
to do when building an app with
要做的事
these is you're going to
就是你需要对
instantiate an
AVSampleBufferRenderSynchronizer
AVSampleBufferRender
以及
Synchronizer and
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer.
进行实例化
Now of these classes, the
在这些分类当中
AudioRenderer class is the one
类型 AudioRenderer
that is responsible for
负责
rendering the audio, and the
对音频进行解析
Synchronizer class is the one
类型 Synchronizer 负责
that's responsible for
建立媒体的
establishing the media timeline.
时间线
Now, there's good reason, you
你可能有充足的理由去问
may be asking yourself, why are
为什么它们被分成两类
they two classes, why didn't you
为什么不把它们
roll it into one?
合二为一
Well, I assure you there's a
我向你保证
good reason.
这么做有充足的理由
We'll talk about that later.
但我们晚一点再告诉你原因
But never the less,
不过
AudioRenderer it does the
AudioRenderer 它确实
rendering of the audio.
负责解析音频
The Synchronizer establishes the
Synchronizer 是建立
media timeline.
媒体的时间线
So, after you've instantiated
所以当你实例化了之后
these, you add the AudioRenderer
你可以把 AudioRenderer
to the Synchronizer.
添加到 Synchronizer
This tells the AudioRenderer to
这么做是告诉 AudioRenderer
follow the media timeline
要去跟从由 Synchronizer 建立的
established by the Synchronizer.
媒体时间线
Now, as you begin working with
现在当你开始和
an AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer,
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer
one of the things it's going to
开始工作
do is it's going to tell you
它会告诉你
when it wants more media data.
它在什么时间需要更多的媒体数据
And when it tells you that it
而当它告诉你它需要
wants more media data, in
更多的媒体数据时
response, you should feed it.
作为回应 你应该反馈给它
So, give it some audio data.
给它提供一些音频数据
And after you've done that, you
完成这些之后
can begin playback by setting
你就可以把 Synchronizer 的
the rate of 1 on the
Rate 设为 1
Synchronizer.
然后开始播放
And after you've set the rate of
在你把 Synchronizer 的 rate 设为 1 之后
1 on the Synchronizer, audio
音频数据将开始
data will begin flowing out of
从 AudioRenderer 中
the AudioRenderer.
流出
So, that's the basic high-level
这就是基本的非常概括的
overview of how you build a
介绍教你如何用
playback engine, with
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer 和
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer and
AVSampleBufferRender
AVSampleBufferRender
Synchronizer
Synchronizer.
来建立播放引擎
Now I'd like to invite my
现在我要邀请我的同事
colleague Adam Sonnanstine up on
Adam Sonnanstine 上台
stage to give a demo of this.
为大家做一个演示
[ Applause ]
鼓掌
&gt;&gt; Thank you, David.
&gt;&gt;  谢谢 David
I'm very happy to be here today
今天我很高兴在这里
to demonstrate AirPlay 2 and its
为大家演示 AirPlay 2
enhanced reliability and
以及它更强大的可靠性
robustness.
和稳定性
I'm going to do that using this
我将用这个
sample application that we've
我们开发的
developed.
样品 App 来演示
And this application will be
这个 App
available as sample code shortly
在 WWDC 结束后
after the conference ends.
很快就会在样本代码中提供出来
And we also have an Apple TV on
我们在台上还准备了一台苹果电视
stage so I can demonstrate
用于演示
AirPlaying from the phone to the
分别用 AirPlay 和 AirPlay 2
Apple TV both with current
两种方式
AirPlay and with AirPlay 2.
将播放内容从手机传输到苹果电视上
So let's take a look at the app.
我们先来看看这个 App
You can see it's just a simple
你可以看到它只是一个简单的
sort of stripped down music
精简的音乐播放器的
player interface.
交互界面
We have this nice AirPlay or
这里可以看到
sorry Control Center integration
控制中心的整合
because I've adopted the
因为我嵌入了 MediaPlayer 的 API
MediaPlayer APIs that David
就像 David 刚才
mentioned before.
提到的那样
So, I'm just going to go ahead
我要开始尝试
and start playing.
播放了
And so you can hear it, I'll
你能够听到它
start AirPlaying to my Apple TV.
我先用 AirPlay 投射到我的苹果电视上
[music] Now this app has not yet
这款 App 现在还没有
been optimized for AirPlay 2 so
优化到 AirPlay 2
I just want to give you a base
我只是想给大家看一下
line of what the performance is
AirPlay 的表现
with the current AirPlay.
大概是什么样子
And I'm going to do that, I want
我希望你们想象一下
you to imagine that you are
自己正坐在客厅的
enjoying this music sitting on
沙发上
my couch in my living room, the
享受这段音乐
music being streamed from my
音乐从我的手机
phone to my Apple TV and I
流向我的苹果电视
decide that it's a good time to
现在我决定
walk outside with the phone in
把手机放在口袋里
my pocket to take out the trash,
出门倒垃圾
maybe to, walking right outside
这一过程中可能会走出
of my Wi-Fi range, and I'm going
我的 Wi-Fi 覆盖区
to simulate that by using this
我要用这个口袋模拟出门的效果
bag, which shields everything I
这个口袋能阻隔
put inside it from
里面东西发射的所有讯号
electromagnetic radiation going
电磁辐射无法进出
in and from coming out, and that
这个口袋
includes Wi-Fi.
包括 Wi-Fi 信号
So, I'll take my phone, and here
我将带上我的手机走出门
I am walking outside and you can
然后你能听到
hear that almost immediately the
音乐几乎是立刻
music cuts out.
中断了
You've probably experienced
你或许以前也有过
something like this before and
类似的经历
if you're actually sitting in my
如果你正在我家做客
living room, listening to music
享受着这段音乐
you're probably going to think
你可能会认为
I'm not a very good host.
我不是一个称职的主人
So, let's go back and I'll go
让我们继续
ahead and pause the music.
我现在暂停音乐
And we'll switch into Xcode here
让我们换到 Xcode 界面
and I'll show you how you can do
我将向你们展示
a couple of simple steps to opt
如何通过几个简单的步骤
your app, this app into AirPlay
来让这个 App 升级到
2.
AirPlay 2
So, here we are in Xcode and I
来看 Xcode 界面
have just a very small snippet
这里有一段非常短的代码片段
from my application here, the
是我的 App 的
rest of it's implemented in
其余部分放在了
other files.
别的文件中
And I just have a function that
这里有一个
the rest of the app is using to
App 其余部分使用的函数
grab an object that it can use
可用来抓取目标
to actually do the audio
实现音频的
playback.
播放
It's basically a factory
它基本上
function.
是一个工厂函数
And this can return an object
这个函数会返回一个
that conforms to a protocol that
符合某种协议的目标
I've defined elsewhere in the
相关协议我在 App 的其他地方
app.
已经进行了定义
We don't need to look at the
我们不需要探讨细节
details, but it defines methods
但它定义出了
for things like play and pause
诸如播放暂停等
and the sort of basic playback
动作的方法
operations that a player should
这是一个播放器所
do.
需要的
And we have an existing
我们有一个现行的
implementation of this protocol
对于这个协议的实现
which is being used in the demo
刚刚在我们看到的演示中
that we just saw.
使用到了
And what we're going to do right
我们现在要做的
now is I'm going to create a
是创建一个全新的
brand-new implementation of this
音频播放器的实现
audio player, and I'm going to
我将把它命名为
call it SampleBufferAudioPlayer
SampleBufferAudioPlayer
because it's going to be built
因为我们将会用到
using AVSampleBufferAudio
AVSampleBufferAudio
Renderer.
Renderer
I'm just going to preemptively
我将先行
swap that in so that the next
把它替换进来
time we launch the app, it will
这样我们下次启动 App 时
use the new implementation
就可以使用新的实现
instead of the old
而不是旧版的
implementation.
实现了
So, as I mentioned, this class
正如我提到的
is going to be built on top of
这个类将建立在
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer,
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer 的基础上
and we're also going to need to
我们也将会用到
use AVSampleBufferRender
AVSampleBufferRender
Synchronizer.
Synchronizer
These are the classes that David
这些
just introduced to you.
David 已经和你们介绍过了
And I just want to reiterate
我只想重申一下
what David said that AVPlayer
David 刚才所说的
would give you all of the
AVPlayer 拥有我接下来即将
benefits that I'm about to show
展示的所有优点
you, but with a little bit less
而在你这边只需要
work on your part.
做很少的工作就可以了
So, if you're already using
所以如果你已经在使用 AVPlayer
AVPlayer, or you think you can
或者你认为你可以
use AVPlayer, we recommend that
用它
you do that.
我们推荐你这么做
For the rest of you, I want to
至于其余的人我将
show you how to use these new
向你展示如何使用
classes.
这些新的类别
So, once I have my state here,
所以一旦我得到了我的状态
I'm going to hook up my
我将使用 addRenderer 的方法
AudioRenderer with my
将 AudioRenderer 和
RenderSynchronizer using the
RenderSynchronizer 进行连接
addRenderer method, and I'll do
而且我会在
that as soon as my
创建了
SampleBufferAudioPlayer is
SampleBufferAudioPlayer 后
created.
立即这样做
And then we need to interact
然后我们需要与渲染器
with the renderer, and we're
进行互动
going to do that by calling the
调出
requestMediaDataWhenReady
requestMediaDataWhenReady
method.
方法
And what this is going to do is
它所能做的就是
it's going to call a closure in
它将调用我 App 的闭包函数
my app so that I can feed the
以便我可以给
AudioRenderer some more audio
AudioRenderer 提供更多的
data whenever the AudioRenderer
音频数据
decides that it's ready to
只要 AudioRenderer 认为它需要
receive more data.
接收更多的数据
And it will call this closure as
只要它一有需要
often as it needs to to stay
就会调用 App 的闭包函数
full of audio data.
保证始终拥有足够的音频数据
Now within my closure, I'm
在闭包函数内
actually going to loop so that
我将使它循环
I'm going to keep appending more
我将继续追加更多的数据
data as long as the
只要
AudioRenderer is still ready for
AudioRenderer 准备好
more media data.
接收更多的媒体数据
Within my loop, the first thing
在循环中第一件事就是
I need to do is grab my next
就是获取下一段
chunk of audio data and package
音频数据并将它打包成
it as a CMSampleBuffer.
CMSampleBuffer
Now this method here is my app's
这里的这个方法只是
own logic for doing this, for
我的这个 App 自己的
grabbing its next little bit of
抓取后一部分音频数据的
audio data.
逻辑
Your app will have your own
你的 App 可以有
version of this logic, maybe
你自己的逻辑
pulling the data off the network
可以是从网络上抓取数据
or decrypting it from disc.
或从光盘上解码
If you want to see the details
如果你想看我这个版本的更多细节
of my version, once again, check
还是老样子
out the sample code.
去网站上的样本代码查看
And I have this set up to return
这里我有这个设置
an optional CMSampleBuffer and
可以返回一个可选的 CMSampleBuffer
that's just so I can use a nil
这样一来我可以用一个 0 返回值
return value to signal that I've
来标记出
reached the end of data.
已经达到了数据的最末端
Once I have my sample buffer, I
一旦我得到了样本缓冲
turn around and enqueue it into
就可以使用 enqueuer 的方法
the AudioRenderer using the
让它排入
enqueue method.
AudioRenderer
And what this will do is it will
它所要做的就是
hand the audio data off to the
将音频数据交给
renderer so that it can schedule
解析器
it to be played at the
以便在合适的时间
appropriate time.
进行播放
As I mentioned, I'm using a nil
正如刚才提过的
sample buffer to signal that I
我用一个 0 样本缓冲值
don't have any more data.
去标记出后面没有任何数据了
And when that happens I need to
当出现这种情况时
explicitly tell the
我需要明确地告诉
AudioRenderer to stop requesting
AudioRenderer 停止索要
more media data.
更多的媒体数据
If I don't do this, and I exit
如果我不这么做并且退出
my closure, that AudioRenderer
app的闭包函数
is just going to invoke the
那么 AudioRenderer 就会
closure right away, when it's
在再次准备好接收数据时
ready for data again, but since
立刻触发 App 的闭包函数
I don't have anything more to
但我已经没有更多数据提供给它
give it, I don't want that to
我当然不希望
happen.
它这么做
So, I need to tell it to stop.
所以我需要叫它停止
And this function here is pretty
这里的这个函数基本上
much your entire interaction
就是你和 AudioRenderer
with the AudioRenderer for a
的全部互动了
simple use case like this.
这是对于一个简单的使用案例来说
Now, we need to do a couple
现在我们需要和
things with the
RenderSynchronizer
RenderSynchronizer.
一起来做点事情
I have a play method, and all
这里有一个 play 方法
that play really is, is setting
实际上就是将 RenderSynchronizer
the RenderSynchronizer's rate to
的 rate 设为 1
1, which will start playback.
它就会开始播放
I have a little bit of prep work
我有一些准备工作要做
I need to do there, which we
我们不需要关注
won't look at the details, but
细节是怎么做的
it does end up calling this
只需要知道它最后会
start enqueueing method so you
引发 enqueueing 方法
can sort of get a feel for how
你大概能明白
things flow here.
事情是如何一步步进行到这里的了
And I have a little bit of UI
我还有一些 UI 要更新
updating to do every time I play
在我每次播放或暂停的时候
or pause, so this method will
所以这个方法会
dispatch back to the main queue
被派到主要的队列
in order to keep the UI up to
以便让 UI 及时
date.
更新
Similarly, I have a pause
同样的 我还有一个暂停方法
method, and the only difference
唯一的区别就是
here is that it sets the
它将 renderSynchronizer 的
renderSynchronizer's rate to 0.
rate 设为 0
So, now you've seen all of the
那么现在你已经看到了
interaction that we're going to
我们和 AVFoundation
have with AVFoundation.
进行的所有互动
I have one more bit of code I
我还需要再补充
need to drop in, just to make
一点代码
sure my app will build and work
这样才能确保我的 App 顺利运行
correctly, which we won't look
我们不用仔细读它是什么
at the details of, but I'll just
只要加上
drop it there.
就行了
And then, we will rebuild the
然后我们就完成了
application.
对 App 的重建改造
And I seem to have some
好像发生了一些
compilation errors.
编辑错误
So, what I'm going to do is
我现在要做的是
figure out what I did wrong.
找出我哪里做错了
Well, why don't we just take
我们可以移走这个
this and, ah I think I know
啊 我想我知道
what's wrong here.
哪里出问题了
Just drag that over here, and go
把它拖到这里然后
back here and we'll try again.
回到这里我们再试一次
All right, so we got our build
好的 我们已经
ready.
建好了
And now we're relaunching the
现在我们要重启
app.
App
So, we'll switch back to our
回到我们的并排
side by side view.
视窗
And once the app finishes
当 App 完成启动后
launching, I'm going to go ahead
我就要
and restart the music playback.
重新开始音乐的播放
Here we go.
开始吧
And once the music starts
一旦音乐开始播放
playing [music] now we're
现在我们是使用 AirPlay 2
playing using AirPlay 2 from the
从手机投射到苹果电视上
phone to the Apple TV.
进行音乐播放
So, now I want to run the same
我要再现一遍
scenario that I did before using
刚才的情景
our bag again.
再次用到那个口袋
So, let's grab the phone.
让我们拿起手机
And we'll put it in the bag.
把它放进口袋里
Once again, here's me taking the
再一次我拿着手机出去
phone outside, outside of Wi-Fi
走出了 Wi-Fi
range.
的覆盖区
I'll fold up the bag nice and
我来封严
tight.
袋子封口
And as you can see, where as in
正如你所看到的
the first demo, the music cut
在第一次的演示中
out almost immediately, now that
音乐几乎是立刻中断了
we're using AirPlay 2, the music
但对于这次使用的 AirPlay 2
can keep playing even through
音乐是一直在播放
these sorts of minor Wi-Fi
尽管遭到了一些
interruptions.
轻微的 Wi-Fi 干扰
So, that's the power of AirPlay
这就是 AirPlay 2
2 using AVSampleBufferAudio
组合上 AVSampleBufferAudio
Renderer.
Renderer 产生的魔力
Thank you very much and back to
非常感谢
David.
现在把现场交还给 David
[ Applause ]
鼓掌
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Adam.
&gt;&gt;  感谢 Adam
So, now that we've shown, walked
我们已经带着大家观看了
you through the steps to create
创建一个简单 App 的步骤
a simple app with
我们用到了 AVSampleBufferAudio
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer and
Renderer 以及
AVSampleBufferRender
AVSampleBufferRender
Synchronizer, let's move on to
Synchronizer
some more advanced playback
下面来看看更多
scenarios that you may be, you
更复杂的播放场景
may encounter when using these
你在使用这些 API 时
API.
也许会需要用到
So, what we're going to talk
我们在这一段落
about in this section is audio
要讲到的是
buffer levels of
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer.
的音频缓冲级别
We're going to talk to about how
我们将谈到如何执行一个 seek
to implement a seek, how to
如何执行播放队列
implement play queues, some of
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer
the support audio formats with
所支持的
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer,
部分音频格式
and lastly, we're going to take
最后我们要扯远一些
a slight detour and talk about
谈一谈视频同步
video synchronization.
的问题
So, let's jump into the next
那么让我们来进入下一个部分
section and talk about the audio
先来说说
buffer levels of
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer.
的音频缓冲级别
So, what am I talking about?
我指的是什么呢
I'm talking about the fact that
我指的是
the amount of audio data request
App 中 AVSampleBufferAudio
by an AVSampleBufferAudio
Renderer
Renderer of your app will vary
对于音频数据的需求量
depending on the current route.
会依据现有的路由而变化
So, let's take a look at this
让我们通过图表
pictorially.
来了解一下
Here I've drawn a media timeline
这里我画出了一条媒体时间线
and I'm going to drop in the
在这儿放下一个
playhead.
播放头
And when you're playing back
当你在本地播放时
locally, the AudioRenderer is
AudioRenderer 只要求
only going to ask for a few
播放头
seconds ahead of the playhead.
前几秒的内容
So, that is where the, that is
那就是你应该
where you should enqueue to, as
排入队列的部分
much as it asks for.
按它所要求的
And as you play, again you're
随着你继续播放
just going to enqueue a few
把播放头的右边几秒
seconds ahead of the app.
排入队列即可
But suppose your user suddenly
但假设用户突然决定
decides to route to an AirPlay 2
要投射到一个
speaker.
AirPlay 2 音箱
Now when that happens, the
这种情况发生时
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer is
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer 将
going to ask for up to multiple
要求播放头右边
minutes ahead of the playhead.
几分钟的长度
And once again, when you hit
再次当你按下播放
play, you'll work multiple
你需要在播放头右边几分钟
minutes ahead of the playhead.
开始工作
Now the key here, is that the
这里的关键是
amount of data requested by
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer
需要多少数据量
varies depending on where the
取决于音频当下的传输路径
audio is currently routed.
是在哪里
If it's routed locally, this
如果音频是本地传输
will just be seconds, to
这一过程可能只需要几秒
Bluetooth seconds, to an AirPlay
通过蓝牙 需要几秒钟
1 speaker seconds.
通过 AirPlay 1 代的音箱也是几秒钟
But as soon as the user routes
但如果用户是将音频内容
your audio content to an AirPlay
传输到支持 AirPlay 2 的音箱上
2 speaker, that AudioRenderer is
那么 AudioRenderer 将会
going to get really hungry and
非常“饥饿”
it's going to ask for multiple
对于音频数据
minutes of audio data.
它可能会需要几分钟的时间
And the key here is that your
重点是你的 App
app should be ready to handle
必须有所准备
these changes.
来处理这些变化
All right, next let's talk about
好的 接下来让我们谈谈
seek.
seek
So, what is a seek?
什么是 seek
Well a seek very quick, very
Seek 简单来说就是
simply, is manually changing the
手动改变
location of the playhead.
播放头的位置
So, again let's draw out our
我们再来画出
media timeline that we just saw
刚才看到的
a moment ago.
媒体时间线
Put in the playhead, and talk
放入播放头
about local play or talk about
我们来进行本地播放
standard playback scenario.
或者说是标准的播放场景
User hits play, and then after
用户点击播放
it plays for a little bit the
然后当音频开始播放后
user decides you know what, I
用户决定
want to seek further into the
我想要在这一曲目中
track.
向后去 seek
So, they pick up the playhead
于是他们抬起播放头
and they drag it.
并向右拖动
So, they've asked for a seek.
他们要求 seek
So, how do we handle this with
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer?
是如何处理这种情况的
Well it's actually really easy.
其实是非常容易的
The first thing that you're
你要做的第一件事
going to do is you're going to
就是要
stop.
停止
You're going to stop playback of
停止 AVSampleBufferRender
the AVSampleBufferRender
Synchronizer 的播放
Synchronizer and you're going to
并停止
stop enqueueing media data into
往 AVSampleBufferAudioRenderer 里
the AVSampleBufferAudio
继续排列
Renderer.
媒体数据
Next, you're going to issue a
下一步你要在
flush on the
SampleBufferAudioRenderer
SampleBufferAudioRenderer which
发布一个 flush
will clear out all media data
它将清除已经排列起来的
that's already been enqueued.
所有媒体数据
And at that point, you're free
那时你就可以
to begin audio, re-enqueueing
在任意媒体时间上
audio data at any media time, so
开始重新排列音频数据
you do it beginning at the seek
也就是在 seek 所在的时间点
to time.
开始重新排列
And after you've enqueued media
当你在 seek 所在的时间点
data the seek to time, kick off
排列了媒体数据后
playback once again and there
再次开始播放
you go.
好了
So, that's a seek.
这就是 seek
So, now that I've shown you how
现在我已经向你展示了
seek works, let's take a look at
Seek 是如何工作的
how you would implement that in
让我们来看看如何在代码中执行它
code, by extending Adam's app
我们要在 Adam 的 App 中
with a method called
使用一个叫做 seektoMediaTime
seek(toMediaTime.
的方法
So, how do we implement this?
具体怎么做呢
Well it's pretty easy.
非常简单
The first thing we're going to
第一件事就是
do is we're going to tell the
我们要告诉
renderSynchronizer to stop
RenderSynchronizer 停止播放
playback by setting the rate to
做法是
0.
把 rate 设为 0
And then we're going to tell the
然后告诉 AudioRenderer
AudioRenderer to stop requesting
停止索要
media data.
媒体数据
Next, we're going flush the
然后我们将清理
AudioRenderer to clear out all
AudioRenderer
the old audio data we've
以便清空队列中的
enqueued.
旧的音频数据
And then we're going to call
然后我们在调用一些 App
some app specific code, that
特别代码
tells your sample generating
它将告诉你的样本生成代码
code that the next sample that
要准备的下一段样本
it should prepare is at that
位置在
seek to time.
seek 处
Remember your app is responsible
记住你的 App 有责任
for producing the audio data
在使用这个 API 时
when using this API, so you need
去提供音频数据
to instruct it where the next
所以你要告诉它
audio sample should be generated
下一段音频样本应该
from.
从哪里生成
And after that happens, you can
之后
reinstall your closure on the
你可以重新设置
AudioRenderer to tell it to call
AudioRenderer 的闭包函数
you back for more audio data.
让它去重新调用要求更多数据
And you can set a rate to 1 on
你可以把 RenderSynchronizer
the RenderSynchronizer.
rate 设为 1
Pretty simple.
比较简单
So, that's seek.
那就是 seek
Let's get into something more
让我们来看看
interesting which is play
更有趣的内容吧
queues.
播放队列
And what is a play queue?
什么是播放队列
Well here we have a screenshot
我们这里有一张
from Adam's app.
Adam 的 App 截图
And a play queue is very simple
播放队列很简单
is, you know, you order a set of
就是你将一系列的条目
items.
进行排序
I hit play on one and they all
我点击播放后
play out in order.
它们就会按顺序逐一播放
So, if we take these, this play
我们来看看这个播放队列
queue and we lay it out on that
把它在媒体时间线上
media timeline, what we're going
列出来
to see is Item 1 followed by
能看到条目 1 的后面是条目 2
Item 2, followed by Item 3.
然后是条目 3
That's just a very generic look
这就是一个非常常见的样子
of those items laid out on this
这些条目平铺
timeline we've been showing.
在时间线上
But if we dig into the timelines
但如果我们仔细研究
especially we're going to see
尤其是对每一个条目的
the timelines of each item,
时间线进行仔细观察
we're going to see something
我们就会发现有些地方
slightly different.
是存在细小差别的
Let's suppose hypothetically
让我们假设
that each item is 100 seconds in
每个条目的长度
length.
是 100 秒
That means that each item will
这就意味着每个条目
go from 0 to 100, 0 to 100, 0 to
都是从
100.
0 到 100
Of course the AudioRenderer
当然 AudioRenderer
knows nothing about these
是不知道这些
individual items.
条目的信息的
All the AudioRenderer has is a
AudioRenderer 所知道的
continuous media timeline.
只是一条连续的媒体时间线
So, as you enqueue audio data
所以当你让音频数据排队
into the AVSampleBufferAudio
进入 AVSampleBufferAudio
Renderer, you may need to offset
Renderer
from the item's natural timeline
你就需要将条目的自然时间线
to the continuous timeline of
变成一条 AVSampleBufferAudio
the AVSampleBufferAudio
Renderer
Renderer.
连续的时间线
And again, let's take a look at
让我们再看看
this enqueuing animation that
刚才看过的
we've seen before.
这个排队列的动画
Here are I'm playing back
这里我正在播放本地音频
locally and I've just enqueued a
我刚刚把
few seconds ahead of the
播放头右边的几秒
playhead and as you can see I'm
排入队列
going to queue each item as I go
正如你所看到的 我会把这些条目
through it.
按顺序排列进来
And if the user is routed to an
如果用户是要投射到
AirPlay 2 speaker, and we're
AirPlay 2 音箱 那我们就要
working well ahead of the
在播放头右边较远的地方开始工作
playhead, same idea.
但还是一个道理
You're just going to enqueue
你只要把播放头右边的部分
ever so slightly ahead of the
多放一些到
playhead.
队列里就行
All right.
好了
So, that's the simple idea of
这就是播放队列的
play queues.
基本概念
Let's get into something a
接下来就
little more interesting,
更有趣了
editing.
编辑队列
And in this hypothetical
在这个假设的情景中
example, let's suppose the user
让我们假设用户决定
decides they don't want to
他们不想听
listen to Item 2 anymore.
条目 2 了
So, they remove it from the
他们就把它移出队列
queue, and so items 3 and 4
于是条目 3 和条目 4
shift over in place.
往前移替代了它的位置
Now, when that happens, it's not
这种情况
a big deal.
没什么复杂的
The user will expect Item 1 to
用户会预期条目 1 播放完
play, followed by Item 3, and
然后是条目 3
followed by Item 4.
再是条目 4
But that's a really relatively
不过这是一个相当简单的
simple case of play queue
编辑播放队列的例子
editing, where I, made the edit
在播放前
before playback is engaged.
我就对队列进行了编辑
But since we're working well
但我们在使用
ahead of the playhead oftentimes
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer 时
when using the
经常要提前载入
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer,
播放头右边很长一段的内容
you could run into a situation
你很可能遇到这样的情况
like this, where the user is
当用户
instantiating, or initiated
开始
playback.
播放
You're still playing Item 1, but
你此刻还在播放条目 1
you've begin to enqueue media
但条目 2 的媒体数据
data from Item 2.
已经进入队列载入
And then the user decides they
这时用户决定
don't want to listen to Item 2
不想听
anymore.
条目 2 了
So, what the user expects is
于是用户期待着
Item 2 disappears, Items 3 and 4
条目 2 消失
shift over.
条目 3 和 4 替换上来
And once again, what the user
再一次
expects is that after Item 1,
用户期待着
the currently playing track
在条目 1 之后
plays, Item 3 will begin to
条目 3  会开始
play.
播放
But if we do nothing at this
如果我们此时什么都不做
point, since we've already
此时条目 2 的音频数据
enqueued audio data from Item 2
已经排列在
into the AudioRenderer, well
AudioRenderer 中
that's what we're going to hear,
接下来我们就会听到条目 2 播放
a blip of that, because we have
然后声音突然中断
the wrong audio data in the
因为我们在
AudioRenderer.
AudioRenderer 中存入了错误的数据
So, what do we do here?
那我们该怎么做呢
Well it's actually relatively
其实也容易处理
simple to handle, because
因为在 Source Time 里
there's a command called Flush
有一个指令
from Source Time.
叫做 Flush
And what this command Flush from
这个指令的功能
Source Time does, what it means,
它的意思
is that given this time that I
就是在我指定的时间点
specify to you, I want you to
我希望你
throw away all of the media data
清除时间线上这个时间点以后的
on the timeline after it.
所有媒体数据
So, here I'm going to call Flush
我在这里调用
from Source Time with the source
Flush from Source Time
time pointing at the time in the
指定连续时间线上的
continuous timeline that it's
这个时间点
the transition from Item 1 to
连续的时间线为
the next item.
条目1和下一个条目提供完美过渡
So, I call that and it throws
于是我就调用这个指令
away all the media data.
它就清空了所有的媒体数据
Next thing that it does, is it
它要做的下一件事
resets the pointer to the last
就是把指针重新放到
enqueued sample buffer to that
指定时间点后正在队列中的样本缓冲
source time, so then I'm free to
之后我就可以
enqueue media data from Item 3.
把条目 3 的 媒体数据排入队列了
And of course, playback
当然
progresses and we're good to go.
随着音频播放 问题迎刃而解
The key point about this is, for
值得注意的一点是
the animation purposes in this
在刚才的动画演示中
talk, I showed it may look like
看起来好像播放被暂停了
playback was paused, but you can
但实际上
actually execute this command
你可以在音频播放的过程中
while playback is engaged, so it
执行这个指令
can be totally transparent to
这个操作完全可以
your users.
对你的用户
All right.
公开
So, let's talk about the steps
接下来我们说说执行
involved in executing the flush
这个 flush from source time 指令
from source time.
所需要的步骤
There's basically three of them.
大致来说有三步
First is, stop enqueueing audio
第一步 停止在渲染器中
data in the renderer.
列入音频数据
Note that I'm not saying stop
注意 我说的不是停止播放
playback, because again you
因为你不需要
don't have to do that.
这么做
Then you issue the
然后你就发布
flushfromSourceTime and after
Flush from SourceTime 的指令
you've issued the
在你发布
flushfromSourceTime, well that
Flush from SourceTime 之后
flush from source is an
flush from sourcetime 是一个
asynchronous option, operation
非同步的操作
into which you pass a closure.
在这里你可以传递一个闭包函数
Well, you should wait for the
你需要等待回调函数
callback to be called.
的发出
Now there are few gotchas with
这里还有几个小的技巧
this, even though it's a
虽说它是一个
relatively simple operation, and
相对简单的操作
the first is that the flush may
第一点就是  flush 有可能会
fail.
失败
Now, why may it fail?
为什么会失败
Well, suppose the source time
假如你指定的时间点
the you specified is too close
距离播放头太接近
to or behind the playhead.
或者是放在了播放头的左边
Well in those situations, we may
在这些情况下
not be able to get the audio
我们可能无法从
data back from the audio
音频硬件中获得
hardware.
音频的数据了
And in those cases well, rather
在这样的情况下
than leaving you in an unknown
与其让你陷入未知的状态
state where you may play out
可能会播放过期数据
stale data, we're just going to
我们宁愿选择让这个
fail the operation and it's, and
操作失败
it's going to be as if it was
看起来像是这个指令
never issued in the first place.
从没被发布过一样
So, the second gotcha which is
第二点小技巧是
really just the other side of
正如凡事都有利有弊
the same coin is that you need
你需要等待
to wait for the callback.
回调函数
So, you should wait for the
这个回调函数
callback which will tell you
将告诉你
whether or not that flush
Flush 是否失败了
failed, and if it did you need
如果它失败了
to take the appropriate action.
你需要采取相应的措施
So, let's take a look at this in
让我们来看看相应的代码
code, again by extended the
还是刚才的样本 App
sample app by calling a method
通过引用一个方法
called -- by implementing a
通过执行一个方法
method called
叫做
FlushfromSourceTime, perform
FlushfromSourceTime
FlushfromSourceTime.
来执行 FlushfromSourceTime
So, once again, in this method
再一次 在这个方法中
the first thing you're going to
你需要做的头件事
do is you're going to tell the
就是通知
AudioRenderer to stop requesting
AudioRenderer 停止
media data.
索要媒体数据
And then you're likely to call
之后你可能想去调用
some app specific logic to
一些 App 特定的逻辑
really ensure that no media,
以确保没有
additional media data is
更多的媒体数据
enqueued.
被排入队列
This is really important,
这点至关重要
because this is an asynchronous
因为这是一个非同步的操作
operation so it's naturally
所以它本身就
racy.
有一定风险
So, we want to make sure that
所以我们希望能确保
you're not enqueueing any
在 FlushfromSourceTime 的运行过程中
additional audio data while that
你没有将更多的音频数据
FlushfromSourceTime is flight.
排入队列中
So, after you've made sure that
当你确信
you're no longer enqueueing
你没有将
audio data in the AudioRenderer,
更多的音频数据排入 AudioRenderer
you can actually execute the
这时就可以执行
FlushfromSourceTime.
FlushfromSourceTime 了
Again, you'll pass in a closure
再次 你可以传递一个闭包函数
because this is an asynchronous
因为这是一个非同步的
operation.
操作
And then closure will tell you
这个闭包函数会告诉你
then whether or not the call to
对于闭包函数的调用
the closure will tell you
是否
whether or not the flush
Flush 是否
succeeded.
成功
If it succeeded as I'm showing
如果像我这里演示的这样 成功了
here, well, the first thing
你之后要做的第一件事就是
you're going to do is again
再一次
you're going to tell your sample
告诉你的负责样本生成的 App
generating app, your app's
然后 App 的样本生成代码
sample generating code to begin
就开始
preparing samples at that source
从指定的时间点处
time.
准备样本
And then you can reinstall your
然后你可以重新调用你的
callback closure and begin
回调函数
enqueueing again.
并再次开始排入队列
Of course, the flush may fail,
当然 这里的 flush 有可能会失败
in here it's really app specific
这时你想如何处理
logic to decide what you want to
就真的全靠 App
do in these situations.
明确的逻辑来决定了
Maybe you want to just advance
或许你想要进入
to the next track.
下一个播放曲目
Maybe you want to execute a full
或许你想要执行一个彻底的 flush
flush and glitch playback, it's
清除播放的小差错
really up to you.
怎么做全凭你决定
So, that's play queues and Flush
以上就是播放队列和
from Source Time.
Flush from Source Time
Let's move on to the supported
下面我们来聊聊
audio formats in
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer.
支持的音频格式
So, what audio formats does the
那么  AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer
都支持哪些
support?
音频格式呢
Well good news, basically all
好消息是 基本上所有
platform supported audio formats
平台支持的音频格式
are also supported by the
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer 也都
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer.
支持
So, this includes LPCM, AAC,
这就包括了 LPCM AAC
mp3, Apple Lossless, lots of
mp3 Apple Lossless
sample rates, lots of bit
包括各种采样率
depths.
各种位深
And additionally, mixed formats
而且 不同格式的音频
may be enqueued.
有时也可以排入同一队列
If Item 1 is AAC at 44.1 you can
如果条目 1 是一个采样率为 44.1 的 AAC 音频
then enqueue that and then MP3
你也可以在它后面排入 48 k 的 MP 3 音频
at 48k and 16bit Apple Lossless
以及 16 位 48 khz 的
at 48 kilohertz.
Apple Lossless 音频
You can just enqueue the audio
你可以让这几种音频的数据
data from each of these back to
一个接一个地入列
back and we will take care of
我们会替你解决
the format transitions for you.
格式转换的问题
So, those are the supported
这就介绍完了
formats.
支持的格式
Let's talk about the preferred
下面来说说
So, because we can play anything
既然我们能播放任何格式
just give us what you got.
你有什么都可以给我们
You have LPCM, give it to us,
你有 LPCM 丢给我们
encoded give it to us.
经过编码的 丢给我们
But one caveat there is all
预先提醒一下
things being equal, if you have
在其他条件都一样的前提下
a decision between encoded or
如果你需要在经过编码的音频
PCM, we would prefer the
和 PCM 中间做出选择
encoded, but don't do any
我们会偏向经过编码的音频
special logic to give us that.
但不要添加特别的逻辑进去
Just give us what you have.
有什么直接丢给我们就好
And we prefer interleaved
此外 我们还更喜欢
channel formats and 1 to 2
交叉容错通道格式以及
seconds of audio per
包含 1 到 2 秒的音频缓冲的
CMSampleBuffer.
CMSampleBuffer 格式
All right, now I'd like to take
好的 现在我想把话题稍微扯远一点
a slight detour and talk about
来谈谈
video synchronization.
视频同步的问题
Now, you may be wondering why
你可能会奇怪
we're talking about video in a
为什么我们要在一个主讲
AirPlay talk that's mainly about
AirPlay 音频的演讲中
audio.
谈到视频
And it's because the classes
原因就是
that we're introducing today not
今天我们介绍的类别
only are they good for AirPlay 2
它们不仅适用于 AirPlay  2
but they're also just really
它们也是
good playback APIs for general
非常好的播放 API
use cases.
即使对于一般的使用来说
And you may want to use them to
你也许想用它们来
play video.
播放视频
Now, once again, if you can use
再说一遍 如果你能使用
AVPlayer, please use that.
AVPlayer  请选择它
But if you can't use AVPlayer
但如果你无法使用 AVPlayer
and you want to play video, here
你又想播放视频
you go.
那么看好了
So, let's refer, jump back to a
让我们回到
block diagram that we showed
刚才在演讲中展示过的
earlier in the presentation.
框架图中
We've got the Client App, the
这里有客户端 App
AudioRenderer and the
AudioRenderer 以及
Synchronizer.
Synchronizer
Well, if I simply move those out
如果我把它们移出去
of the way, I can make room for
就有空间放入
a new renderer class and here
一个新的渲染器类别
I'm going to add an
我打算加入一个
AVSampleBufferDisplayLayer.
AVSampleBufferDisplayLayer
Now for those of you who are
如果你们对
AVSampleBufferDisplayLayer, it's
不熟悉的话
a class similar to the new
它是一个类似于新的
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer,
AVSampleBufferAudio Renderer 的类别
except this one is geared
唯一差别是它
towards video.
更面向视频内容
It's been around for quite a
它已经推出了一段时间
while and there's some
你能在开发者网站上
documentation and sample code on
找到相关的文件和
the developer website.
样本代码
But new in these releases is the
但这次发布中的新鲜内容是
idea that you can have its
你可以用 RenderSynchronizer
timeline controlled by a
去控制它的
RenderSynchronizer.
时间线
You can add it to a
你可以把它加到
RenderSynchronizer just as you
RenderSynchronizer 里
add the AudioRenderer to your
就像你把 AudioRenderer 加入到
And this is really cool.
这真的很酷
Because then you can add the
因为这样一来你就能
audio data to the AudioRenderer.
把音频数据加到 AudioRenderer 里
The video data to the video
把视频数据加到视频渲染器中
renderer, set a rate of 1 on the
设同步器的 rate 为 1
Synchronizer, and because
因为
they're tied to the same
它们使用的是同一个时间线
timeline, that will come out in
出来后是同步的
sync.
结果
Now a couple words of caution,
有几句提醒
the video will not be AirPlayed,
视频不会被 AirPlay 投射
and additionally when you're
而且当你在使用长形时
using long-form you can only add
你只能把一个
one AudioRenderer to a
AudioRenderer 加进
RenderSynchronizer.
RenderSynchronizer
But never the less, I think you
不过我觉得你已经能够
can see the power in this and
感受到这个架构中的
flexibility in this architecture
力量以及灵活性
and I'm sure you'll come up with
我相信你们一定会
some really cool use case,
摸索出一些非常酷的使用实例
applications and we're excited
和应用
to find out what you can do.
我们很期待你们的探索结果
All right.
好的
Lastly, let's talk about the
最后我们来谈谈
availability of AirPlay 2.
AirPlay 2 的可用性
So, I'm happy to say that the
我很高兴地说
APIs that I've discussed today
我今天和大家讨论的这些 API
plus the advanced buffering are
以及改进后的缓冲系统
all available in the beta that
都在你们今天能够进入的
you guys have access to today.
测试版中可以使用
And you simply set the AirPlay 2
如果你把开发人员面板上的
toggle in the developer pane,
AirPlay 2 切换键
flip that on.
点开
And then you can use an updated
之后就能使用一个升级后的苹果电视
Apple TV as your AirPlay 2
它可以作为 AirPlay 2 的接收端
receiver and send to it.
发送给它
In an upcoming beta, we're going
在即将发布的测试版中
to enable multi-room audio.
我们将实现多房间音频控制功能
And lastly, this will be
最后一点 这些将在
available to customers in an
即将发布的版本中
upcoming release.
供用户使用
Let's go through the summary.
我们来总结一下
We've covered a lot today.
今天讲了很多内容
So, AirPlay 2 introduces many
AirPlay 2 在音频方面
new features for audio.
有很多新的功能
Long-form audio applications can
使用长形音频的应用
enable them with the steps that
按照我今天概括的步骤去做
I've outlined today.
就可以实现这些功能
And AirPlay 2 adoption can begin
嵌入 AirPlay 2
with the beta you guys all have
可以从你们手中的测试版
in your hands.
开始尝试
Additional information, this
还有一些信息
website will have the
这个网站将提供
presentation that we've gone
我们今天的演讲内容
over today, and there will be
样本代码也即将
sample code available soon.
提供给大家
A couple sessions that we've
还有我们刚才提到的
talked about earlier.
几个介绍会
There's the What's New in Audio
包括 What's New in Audio 介绍会
session, that's the one that
它更加深入地
will discuss long-form in more
讨论了长形音频
depth and also Introducing
同时介绍了
MusicKit.
MusicKit
That's one that you should check
推荐大家去
out.
看看
Thank you very much and I hope
非常感谢
you have a great rest of the
希望大家这星期余下的时间
week.
也过得愉快